

LATA BHARTI SONWANI

Qualification: [B.Sc. (Honors), B.Ed., M.Sc. (Bio-Science), MBA-HR]; Science/Biology Teacher: British Curriculum, Indian Curriculum IGCSE. CBSE

Email: sonwani.lata@gmail.com; Mob: +971 50 7288618

UAE VISA: Family (Sponsor) Visa

PROFILE

Having handful experience of 4.5 years in the field of education, I am a supporter and promoter of child centric education, have created lesson plans, tracked students' progress and presented information to parents, worked with the school administration, prepared students for standardized tests, thus led the smooth functioning of primary and secondary sections.

Possess exceptional presentation, communication, interpersonal and leadership skills

EDUCATION

Master's in Business Administration (HR)

2015-2017 Pune University, Pune, IN

Bachelor of Education

2012 - 2013

Pt. Ravishankar Shukla Univ., Raipur, IN

Masters of Science

(Five Years Integrated Course) **Bachelor of Science** (Honors)

2007-2012

Pt. Ravishankar Shukla Univ., Raipur, IN

12th and 10th from **CBSE**D.A.V. Public School, Sonadih (C.G.)
IN
2005 – 2007

*All certificates from Graduation onwards attested by UAE Ministry

EXPERIENCE

GEMS WESTMINSTER SCHOOL - SHARJAH, UAE

National Curriculum for England (NCfE) & UK IGCSE

KS 3-4, Food & Nutrition / Biology Teacher Cover Jan 2023 – March 2023

JOB RESPONSIBILITIES

- Design and organize the lesson plans and other instructional programs
- Plan, schedule and implement British Curriculum based classes

GEMS - THE WESTMINSTER SCHOOL, DUBAI, UAE

National Curriculum for England (NCfE) International Primary Curriculum (IPC)

KS 2, Science Teacher Cover Sept 2022 – Nov 2022 [3Months]

JOB RESPONSIBILITIES

- Provide holistic instructions and guidance to help students explore and understand important concepts in science
- Evaluating students work and recording their performance
- Ensure students achieve their learning objectives with ease
- Implement best teaching practices to enhance studentlearning process

VANASTHALI PUBLIC SCHOOL (CBSE), NEW DELHI, IN

Trained Graduate teacher (Biology)
March 2018 to January 2019 [11 Months]

JOB RESPONSIBILITIES

- Provide consistent and high academic and behavioral expectation
- Helped students to analyze and improve study methods and habits
- Conducted students' assessments and evacuation and provided regular progress

CO AND EXTRA CURRICULAR ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded GOLD MEDAL in BIOSCIENCE(M.Sc.) from Pt. Ravi Shankar Shukla University, Raipur(2013)
- Cleared C.G. Teaching Eligibility Test (2012)
- School Head Girl in D.A.V. School(2007)

WORKSHOP

- Experiential Learning- The classroom Guide by Next Education
- National conference on Advances in Biological Sciences

LEARNING:

- To work collaboratively with team
- To handle 2-3 tasks simultaneously
- To give attention to details

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English, Hindi

BLOSSOM PUBLIC SCHOOL (CBSE), PUNE, IN

Trained Graduate teacher (Biology)
April 2015 – October 2017 [2Yrs 7Months]

JOB RESPONSIBILITIES

- Study guide producer and resource material creator
- Responsible for conducting regular teaching-learning activities, preparing question papers for class assessments
- Compiling the comprehensive results of the same

DRONACHARYA PUBLIC SCHOOL (CBSE), RAIPUR, IN

Post Gradate Teacher (Biology) June 2013 – June 2014 [1 Year]

JOB RESPONSIBILITIES

- Supervising students during experiments and Practical
- Responsible for academic as well as all round development of children
- Responsible for conducting co-curricular activities
- Prepared worksheets for students from class IX and X

PROJECTS

CUSTOMER'S SATISFACTION IN TRAINING AND DEVELOPMENT

Lafarge India Pvt. Ltd. 2 Months Internship (May 2016- June 2016)

Serum Uric Acid Level in Sickle Cell Disease Patients: Under guidance of Dr. P.K. Patra

Pt. Jawaharlal Nehru Medical College, Raipur Chhattisgarh, C.G. IN

6 Months Internship (Jan2012- June2012)